Register of the Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers, 1900-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- Memorabilia, 1929-1965, undated (Boxes 500-504, Box 581)
  - Wisconsin, University of, Degree L.L.D., 1965 June 7; 4.0 folders)
  - Personal records relating to early experience at Oxford as a Rhodes Scholar (Box 502)
  - Personal records relating to parents (Box 503)
    - Hornbeck, M. D. and L. K., diplomas
    - Hornbeck, Lydia K., last illness letters, etc. from Mary Helmle to S. K. H.
    - Hornbeck, Lydia K.
    - Mother's death
    - Father's death
    - Hornbeck, M. D. writings, 2.0 folders)
  - Honors, medals, diplomas, Bibles (Box 504)
  - American flag, undated (Box 581)
- Family and Personal Correspondence File, 1903-1957 (Boxes 505-519)
  Correspondence with family members, friends, and organizations relating to family and personal affairs, arranged by subseries as listed.
  - Family correspondence
    - Letters to parents, 1903-1908; 5.0 folders) (Box 505)
    - Letters to parents, 1909-1914; 5.0 folders) (Box 506)
    - Letters to parents, 1915-1920; 3.0 folders) (Box 507)
    - Letters to parents, 1921-1923; 3.0 folders) (Box 508)
    - Letters to mother, 1903-1905; 1.0 folder)
    - Letters from mother, 1906-1909; 1.0 folder) (Box 509)
    - Letters from father, 1903-1909; 1.0 folder)
    - Letters form parents, 1909-1911; 2.0 folders)
    - Letters from parents, 1912-1917; 5.0 folders) (Box 510)
    - Letters from parents, 1918-1923; 3.0 folders) (Box 511)
    - Family business file, 2.0 folders)
    - Letters to and from parents, 1918-1919 (Box 512)
    - Letters home, 1924-1925; 3.0 folders) (Box 513)
    - 1927-1938, 1944-1945
    - Letters from Vivienne Hornbeck, 1945 (Box 514)
    - 1948-1951
    - Letters not answered, 1952-1953
    - 1953-1956
    - Miscellaneous letters of L. K. and M. D. Hornbeck (Box 515)
    - Miscellaneous, 1.0 folder)
    - Congratulatory letters to S. K. Hornbeck, 1904; 1.0 folder)
    - Letters from mother, 1924-1925; 1.0 folder)
    - Last letters from father, 1923; 1.0 folder)
    - Personal letters, 1960; 1.0 folder)
  - Personal correspondence (Box 516)
    - Apartment, 2139 Wyoming Ave., N. W., circa 1938
    - Athenaeum Club, London
      See also: "Clubs"
    - Beta Theta Pi, 1944
    - Beta Theta Pi, Reception for S. K. H. and V. B. H., 1944-1946
    - Beta Theta Pi, Bigwin and Points East, 1950, 1952
    - Beta Theta Pi Convention, Oxford, 1954
    - Beta Theta Pi, 1953
    - Beta Theta Pi Convention, California, 1953
    - Beta Theta Pi, Old Point Comfort, 1951
    - College Club (Boston Women's), lecture, 1928
    - Clubs
    - Congratulatory messages
    - Cosmos Club, Foreign Affairs Group meeting at, 1962
    - Cosmos Club
    - Christmas Cards and others, 1944
    - Daily appointments
    - Hornbeck, Donald W. (Box 517)
    - Hornbeck family
    - Hornbeck, M. D., Grant Avenue Church, Denver, 1935
    - Horneck guest list, 1946-1947
    - Hornbeck, Harris and Ewing
    - Hornbeck, in department
    - Instructions, travel orders, commission, etc., address to Queen
    - Invitations, acceptances and refusals, 1946
    - Lectures, 1926-1927
    - Letters, 1955
    - Letters to newspapers
    - Marion and Bernice Hornbeck
    - Marion A. Hornbeck
    - Memoirs - Franklin, Massachusetts
    - Personal (Box 518)
    - Personal, 1944
    - Photographs
    - Pioneer, in U. of Denver, 1928 December
    - R. R. Hornbeck, 1931, 1944 ,1957; 2.0 folders)
    - Reviews, 1956
    - Sojourners (National) Club
    - Springfield Century Club
    - Statements by
    - Thank you notes received and sent, 2.0 folders)
    - Travel (Box 519)
    - Travel orders, 1947
    - Trips, SS Memphis, Arizona, etc., 1935
    - Trip to London, 1943 October 4; 2.0 folders)
    - Twentieth Century Club
    - University Club
    - Vivienne
    - Vivienne, 1946 May 20
    - Wellesley Hills Women's Club, Niles, Marion
- Miscellany, 1912-1966 (Boxes 520-560, 578, 586-587)
  - 1920-1928 (Box 520)
  - 1922-1924 (Box 521)
  - 1930-1935 (Box 522)
  - 1936-1939 (Box 523)
  - 1936-1939 (Box 524)
  - 1940-1945 (Box 525)
  - 1941-1944 (Box 526)
  - 1945 (Box 527)
  - 1946 (Box 528)
  - 1945-1949 (Box 529)
  - 1950-1951 (Box 530)
  - 1952-1954 (Box 531)
  - 1955-1966 (Box 532)
  - Special Documents File (Box 533)
    - Intercepted Japanese telegrams and notes from Hornbeck to the Secretary of State, 1941 May 9 - November 30
      - 1) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 May 9
      - 2) Note, unsigned, 1 page, circa 1941 July
      - 3) Note, "We should note," initial SKH, 1 page, undated
      - 4) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 September 17
      - 5) Memorandum, unsigned, 4 pages, 1941 July 23
      - 6) Note, initial SKH, 2 pages, 1941 July 28
      - 7) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 August 2
      - 8) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 August
      - 9) Letter, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 August 16
      - 10) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 September 2
      - 11) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 3 copies, 1941 September 2
      - 12) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 September 3
      - 13) Telegram and note, unsigned, 2 pages, 1941 September 5
      - 14) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 September 10
      - 15) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 September 7
      - 16) Telegram and Note, initial SKH, 2 pages, 2 copies, 1941 October 11
      - 17) Note, initial SKH, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 October 21
      - 18) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 November 4
      - 19) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 3 copies, 1941 November 10
      - 20) Note, initial SKH, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 12
      - 21) Note, initial SKH, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 12
      - 22) Note, initial SKH, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 12
      - 23) Note, initial SKH, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 12
      - 24) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 November 19
      - 25) Note, "We Now Have Clear Evidence," unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, undated
      - 26) Note, "We Have Occasion," unsigned, 1 page, undated
      - 27) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 November 25
      - 28) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 November 30
      - 29) Telegram, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 30
    - Churchill, 1941
      - 1) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 2 copies, 1941 November 6
      - 2) Letter, unsigned, 2 pages, 1941 November 7
      - 3) Note, unsigned, 1 page, 1941 December 8
  - General International Organization, outline (Box 534)
    Three bound volumes
  - Committee on Post War Programs, Military Government of the Far East (Box 535)
  - Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 536)
  - Undated (Box 537)
  - Department of State
    - circa 1939-1942 (Box 538)
    - circa 1938-1945 (Box 539)
    - circa 1937-1942 (Box 540)
    - circa 1939-1941 (Box 541)
  - Essays and bulletins, 1948-1958 (Box 542)
  - Clippings and photocopies (Box 543)
  - China: Newspapers, press clippings (Box 544)
  - China: Memoranda, circa 1920 (Box 545)
    Contains section from Open Door Policy, E. T. Yen.
  - Clippings, memoranda, correspondence (Box 546)
  - Washington Conference, 1921 (Box 547)
  - Genoa Conference, 1922
  - Peking Conference, 1924
  - Large document in unknown language
  - Letters, clippings, advertising (Box 548)
  - "Peace and War," United States Policy, 1931-1941
  - Tentative list of treaty collections, 1919 (Box 549)
  - Treaty of Versailles, with index
  - Review of Washington Conference
  - Administration, Siamese State Railways, 1920
  - Chinese Railway Statistics, 1920
  - Contract for Chinese Government Railways
  - Chinese Railway Statistics, 1916
  - Miscellaneous pamphlets (Box 550)
  - Hornbeck Guest Book
  - Hammond World Atlas
  - Clippings (subject folders)
  - Undated handwritten notes (Box 551)
  - Notes for speeches, 1949-1950
  - Williamstown address, 1929 (Box 552)
  - Treaty of Versailles
  - List of treaties and arrangements in force between Great Britain and China, 1925
  - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 553)
  - Unsorted correspondence and clippings (Box 554)
  - Maps, clippings, library labels, handwritten notes (Box 555)
  - Notes for speeches, circa 1930-1932 (Box 556)
  - Unsorted notes (Box 557)
  - Notes for speeches, circa 1928-1932 (Box 558)
  - Notes for speeches, circa 1930 (Box 559)
  - Geographical Character of Pacific Area, 1926 (Box 560)
  - "The Chinese Tariff,", 1921
  - The Conditions of Peace, 1919
  - State Department memoranda, circa 1932-1934
  - Interview with Hornbeck, 1965
  - Reproduction control slips, undated (Box 578)
    Used in preparation for The Diplomacy of Frustration: The Manchurian Crisis of 1931-1933 as Revealed in the Papers of Stanley K. Hornbeck, published as part of the Hoover Archival Documentaries series.
  - China correspondence, 1912-1913 (Box 586)
  - UN recognition of Communist China, 1951-1954
  - Text & Commentary, Department of State, 1944 July 6 (Box 587)
    Contains information regarding tentative proposals for a General International Organization.
  - Speeches Made on Occasion of the Awarding of the Honorary Degree of Doctor in the Faculty of Law to His Excellency Stanley Kurt Hornbeck, 1947
  - Speeches and writings
    See also: Speeches and Writings series
    - A Brief Study of Some Facts and Many Not-Facts Regarding "China" and United States "China Policy,", 1961
    - China To-Day: Political, 1927
      Three copies, two of which are signed by Hornbeck.
    - Contemporary Politics in the Far East, 1944
    - "Traditional United States 'China Policy'--What, Why & How," lecture, 3 copies, 1961 July
    - The United States and the Netherlands East Indies, 1948
- Card File, 1927-1966 (Boxes 561-577, 584-585)
  Contains lecture notes, news clippings, and other miscellaneous notes organized by subject. Also includes some correspondence and other printed matter.
- Photographs, 1900-1947, undated (Photo file, Boxes 579, 582-583, Map case)
  - 85 photos of Hornbeck's family and ancestors, 1900-1933 (Folder A-B)
  - 25 photos of Stanley K. Hornbeck, mostly portraits, undated (Folder C)
  - 21 photos of Hornbeck's classmates at University of Denver and Oxford, circa 1903-1907 (Folder D)
  - 93 photos of Armenia and work of the American Military Commission to Armenia, 1919 (Folder E)
    List of captions in envelope as well.
  - 93 photos of scenes of daily life on Bali Island, Indonesia, circa 1910 (Folder F)
  - 90 photos of Ambassador and Mrs. Hornbeck at informal social events, 1944-1947 (Folder G)
  - 129 photos of Ambassador and Mrs. Hornbeck with visiting government dignitaries, at formal social events, and at military reviews, 1944-1947 (Folder H-I)
  - 13 photos of Ambassador Hornbeck and staff of U.S. Embassy in The Netherlands, undated (Folder J)
  - 10 photos of Admiral Henry K. Hewitt during his visit with Ambassador Hornbeck, The Hague, The Netherlands, undated (Folder K)
  - 11 photos of Herbert Hoover during his visit with Ambassador Hornbeck, The Hague, The Netherlands, circa 1946 (Folder L)
  - 1 photo of Queen Mother Elizabeth and Lt. Gen. Percival J. Montague, 1946 (Folder M)
  - 1 photo of Secretary of State James F. Byrnes and Foreign Minister Vyacheslav Molotov of the U.S.S.R., undated (Folder N)
  - 32 postcards of European scenic and cultural sites, undated (Folder O)
  - 30 photos of Gen. Eisenhower during his visit to The Netherlands, 1945 (Folder P)
  - 127 photos of scenes in China taken while Hornbeck was an instructor in Chinese Government Colleges, 1909-1913 (Folder Q)
  - 17 photos of friends and colleagues of Hornbeck while he was an instructor in Chinese Government Colleges, 1909-1913 (Folder R)
    Includes group photo of Commission that negotiated the treaty of October 8, 1903 for the extension of commercial relations between the U.S. and China.
  - 25 photos of friends and colleagues of Hornbeck, including Cordell Hull, William R. Castle, Paul S. Reinsch, and Generalissimo and Madame Chiang Kai-shek, undated (Folder S)
  - 3 group photos of Hornbeck's colleagues in the State Department, circa 1930-1940 (Folder T)
    ncludes a group photo of Henry L. Stimson and State Department staff, circa 1930.
  - 3 photos of newspaper cartoons of Hornbeck and 1 photo of a newspaper picture showing Saburo Kurusu (Japanese envoy), Joseph Ballantine (U.S. State Department), and Kiehisaburo Nomura (Japanese Ambassador), 1941-1942 (Folder U)
  - 1 photos of Stanley and Vivian Hornbeck on vacation in the West, circa 1940 (Folder V)
  - 20 miscellaneous and unidentified photos, undated (Folder W, Box 583)
  - 47 oversize photos of Hornbeck, circa 1910-1932 (Boxes 582-583)
    Includes images of Hornbeck's family and classmates; a group photo of the Institute of Pacific Relations Conference in Honolulu (1925); State Department colleagues, including Frank Kellogg and Henry L. Stimson; as well as scenes and friends in China (circa 1910). Photos from envelopes mX, mY, and mZ.
  - 7 photographs of Stanley K. Hornbeck (Box 579)
    Contains 2 portraits of Hornbeck and several group photographs from various unidentified events. 4 of the photographs are framed.
  - 7 oversize photos, 1924-1939 (Box 584, Map case)
    Images include: Secretary Kellogg and State Department personnel, Washington, D.C. (February 1929); the 4th Annual Convention, Military Order of the World War, Boston, Massachusetts (October 1924); University of Denver classmates; The Centenary of Beta Theta Pi, Miami University, Oxford, Ohio (August 7, 1939); and 2nd Annual Luncheon Conference of the National Council vs. Foreign Service Training in Conjunction with National Foreign Trade Council, Hotel Brunswick, Boston, Massachusetts (June 3, 1924).
- Sound Recordings, 1947, undated (Record cabinet, Tape cabinet, Box 588)
  5 sound tape reels, 3 sound discs (lacquer), 15 sound discs (shellac)
  - Linguaphone Conversational Course: French, undated (Box 588)
    15 shellac sound discs containing 30 lessons on how to speak French.
  - United States ambassador's farewell address to Holland, 1947 March 6
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 67008_a_0002435
    The ambassador points out the good points of the country as he sees it. With an introduction by Daniel L. Schorr, the Hague. A paper transcript is available. Digitized use copy from lacquer disc. 1 disc
  - Rest of sound recordings not described.
- Oversize Material, 1856-1948, undated (Box 580, 589, Map case)
  - Certificates, 1869-1948 (Box 580)
    Contains various diplomas and certificates for Stanley K. Hornbeck and his parents, Marquis D. Hornbeck and Lydia Kuhl Hornbeck. Also included are Stanley K. Hornbeck's invitation to the inauguration of Franklin D. Roosevelt, his membership certificate to Phi Beta Kappa Associates, and his parent's marriage license.
  - Poster, undated
    Poster for an IRC event that Hornbeck spoke at.
  - Two drawings depicting a battle in Hangzhou and a naval battle near Taiwan, circa 1912
  - Bound collection of famous Chinese landscape paintings, circa 1918
  - Graphic Scenes in the Japan Expedition by William Heine, 1856
    Contains lithographs. Heine was the official artist of Commodore Matthew C. Perry's expedition to Japan in 1853-1854.
  - Pageant of the Pacific by Miguel Covarrubias, 1940
    Contains six maps illustrating the different aspects of the cultures of the Pacific. Cover for book located in Box 580. Maps located in map case.
  - Shengji Tu, undated
    A book of Confucian parables and poetry with illustrations.
  - Maps, 1913-1926, undated (Box 589)
    Contains maps of Eastern Asia, China, Shanghai, Japan, the Philippines, Mongolia, Oahu, Honolulu, as well as a map of Massachusetts Avenue Park and Massachusetts Avenue Heights in Washington, D.C. Also included are some hand drawn maps of China by Stanley K. Hornbeck and a series of blueprint maps regarding existing and proposed railways in China (1918). Material in English, Chinese, and French.